本字幕由YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
■
翻译：Ｊ小糯    Soomii    红豆包    Iz
校对：Ｊ小糯      时间轴：grace
■
后期：鱼骨头      总监：stephanie
《开心汉堡店》
第一季第十三集
■
新鲜嫩滑的牛肉
Fresh ground meat!
其乐融融的氛围
Great atmosphere!
吉恩  快进来
Gene, bring it in.
快把汉堡服脱下来  要出发了
Get out of that burger suit. We're going.
棒球开赛不等人
Baseball waits for no one.
怎么一股尿骚味  你往这上面撒过尿么
It smells like urine. Did you pee in that?
我得走了
I had to go!
我说过不要往这上撒尿
I told you not to pee in it
尤其是在我洗过之后
after I cleaned up from the...
只有我穿这玩意
I'm the only one who wears it.
干不干净又怎样
What's the difference?
我的老天
Oh, my God.
怎么  尿骚男卖的汉堡
What, you don't want to buy burgers
你不会买么
from a guy who smells like pee?
我又不能把尿憋回去
No one can place where it's coming from.
真不敢相信
I can't believe
你关门就是为了去看棒球比赛
you'll close the restaurant to go to a baseball game.
露易丝  我们不仅是去看比赛
Louise, this isn't just a game.
还去看球场上我们打出的广告
We bought an ad at the ballpark.
这件事值得我们关一天门吧
That's worth closing for, right?
我迫不及待了
Oh, can't wait to see it!
好兴奋呀  我们出名了
It's gonna be so exciting. We're famous.
开心汉堡店
A级牛肉  A+级口味
好像一张热狗包装纸卡在了球网上
It looks like a hot dog wrapper's stuck in the net.
一个小得不能再小的热狗
Like, a really tiny hot dog.
我还以为会比这大一点呢
I did think it was gonna be a little bigger.
如果你登的是"尿壶蛋糕"
I think more people would see your ad
也许看广告的人会多一些
if it was a urinal cake.
坑你爹呢
Are you kidding?
我倒是希望有钱登则尿壶蛋糕的广告
I wish I could afford a urinal cake ad.
一个劲儿提蛋糕  都把我听饿了
All this talk about cake is making me hungry.
我要叫住那个卖冰淇淋三明治的小伙
I'm gonna flag down the ice cream sandwich guy. Hey!
比赛开始
Play ball!
欢迎各位在小联盟的开幕日前来观看比赛
Welcome to opening day of Minor League Baseball.
加油
奇葩狗
为出彩码头  奇葩狗  欢呼吧
Let's hear it for your Wonder Wharf, Wonderdogs!
欢迎奇葩狗的费诺上场
Please give a big Wonderdog welcome to Phe-Nom,
他是韩裔短打高手
the Korean bunt specialist!
我从不知道棒球比赛中有如此多的臀部接触
I never realized baseball had so much butt-touching.
他们就是靠这种方式沟通的  蒂娜
That's how they communicate, Tina.
就像盲人摸盲文  而他们摸的是屁股
It's like Braille, but with butts.
来摸摸我的屁股
Read my butt!
主场
客场
第7局
坏球
好球
我好无聊啊
I'm bored.
无聊的比赛  无聊的运动
Boredom. Boring sports.
第七局中场休息  吉祥物赛跑又要开始了
Hey, it's the seventh-inning stretch. Time for the mascot race.
这个带劲儿啊
Well, hello!
欢迎奇葩狗的老板
Please welcome the owner of the Wonderdogs,
凯尔文・费舍奥德先生
Mr. Calvin Fischoeder!
大鱼
Fish!
赛跑时间又到了
It's that time.
为你喜欢的吉祥物大声欢呼吧
Now cheer for your favorite mascot!
这支球队是费舍奥德先生的吗
Mr. Fischoeder owns the team?
球场  球队  出彩码头  全都是他的
He owns the ballpark, the team, Wonder Wharf.
我要嫁给他
I'm gonna marry that man.
-你给我打住  -我想变成有钱人
- No, you're not. - I wanna be rich!
别害怕
Don't be frightened.
我有枪
I have a gun!
预备...
So, get set...
我之前怎么就没碰上这种比赛呢
Where has this sport been all my life?
你也知道  我整天穿着汉堡服
You know, I wear the burger costume all the time.
老爸  也许我可以下去跑上一两圈呢
Maybe I could race in one of these races, dad.
我敢打赌  要想参赛并非易事  吉恩
I bet it's impossible to get in, Gene.
-你得有门路才能混进去  -你有的啊
- I'm sure you gotta know someone. - You do.
费舍奥德先生  我们的房东嘛
It's Mr. Fischoeder, our landlord.
可是  我无法向
Well, I can't ask a favor
从未准时收到过房租的房东开口求情
of a guy I've never paid rent on time to.
你是他亲儿子  吉恩  他会去求情的
You're his son, Gene. He'll ask him.
-太好了  -我才不去呢
- Yay! - No, I won't.
现在  投手已经站到投球板上了
Now taking the mound to pitch,
名噪一时的职棒前主投
former Major League sensation,
陶彼德・琼斯
Torpedo Jones!
那个不是陶彼...
That can't be the same Torpe...
孩子们  那个人真的是陶彼德・琼斯
Kids, that's the Torpedo Jones!
真不敢相信他还在打球
I can't believe he's still playing.
天啊  他得有我这么大了
God, he must be... my age.
我代表在座列位声明
I speak for everyone here when I say,
"我可不认识什么陶彼德・琼斯"
"I don't know what a Torpedo Jones is."
-我跟你们讲...  -谁稀奇啊
- Let me tell you, nobody... - We don't care.
吉恩  让我说完  没有谁...
Gene, let me finish. Nobody...
"没人"你就别说了呗
That's what I was trying to prevent.
没有谁的投球技术能赶上陶彼德
Nobody pitched like Torpedo.
我有幸看到他人生的巅峰时刻
I was there for his greatest moment,
"凌波微球"
"the pitch".
那是15年前
It was 15 years ago,
可在我记忆中  那仿佛是10年前
but I remember it like it was 10.
他投出了一记漂亮的无影指叉球
His pitch was the split-finger skadootch.
陶彼德用那记投球
Torpedo clinched the pennant for us
赢得了优胜锦旗
with that pitch.
如果他这么有名的话
If he's so good,
为什么我们都没听说过他
why have we never heard of this guy?
那是因为他在大联盟待的时间不长
Well, because he didn't last long in the bigs.
那记无影球也只是众多投球中的一记
You know, the skadootch is just one of those pitches.
当它雄风大振的时候  真的好给力
When it was on, it was really on.
但当它雄风不振的时候...
But when it wasn't...
击破它就好像用球棒打掉婴儿手里的糖果
it's like hitting candy out of a baby's hand with a bat.
因为婴儿手小  所以糖果很难打掉吗
Wait. You mean it's hard because babies' hands are so small?
不  我是说那样很容易
No, it's easy because...
你怎么能对婴儿下手
How could you hit a baby?
现实中不会有人用球棒击打婴儿的小手啦
Nobody would hit a baby's hand with a bat in real life.
我不是很懂
I don't understand.
他被开除是因为他用球棒击打婴儿吗
Was he fired from the bigs 'cause he hit a baby with a bat?
我不想再跟你们说话了
I'm not interested in talking to you anymore.
抱歉  吉恩  哪都看不见费舍奥德
Sorry, Gene. I don't see Fischoeder anywhere.
咱们还是走吧
Let's get going.
没关系啦  我也只是想想而已
That's all right. I only wanted to do it really, really bad.
那个是陶彼德哎
Oh! There's Torpedo!
老爸  跟陶彼德说说参加赛跑的事吧
Dad, ask Torpedo about the mascot races.
也许他能帮个忙呢
Maybe he can get Gene in.
得了吧  孩子们
Kids, come on.
我不想去烦陶彼德  他可是我的偶像
I can't bother Torpedo. He's, like, my role model.
真好笑  你的偶像跟你一样大
Oh, that's creepy. Your role model is the same age as you?
我永远也不会崇拜一个九岁的小屁孩
I would never have another nine-year-old as my role model.
陶彼德
Hey, Torpedo!
我老爸是美国棒球联赛的超级粉丝
My dad is a huge scout for the Baseball League of America!
逗你的啦  他想请你帮个忙
Kidding. But he has a favor to ask you.
你好  我是你的超级粉丝
Hi, I'm a huge fan.
有幸瞻仰"凌波微球"的诞生
You know, I was there for "the pitch".
你想要什么
So, uh, what can I do for ya?
照片  签名
Picture? Autograph?
3块钱一张  5块钱两张
Three bucks each, both for five.
那  我要两张吧
Uh, yeah, both would be great.
老爸
Dad!
还有  我儿子想要参加吉祥物赛跑
Oh, and my kid wants to run in the mascot race.
-您看能不能...  -拉塞尔
- You don't think... - Hey, Russell!
这儿有个小孩想参加吉祥物赛跑
Some kid here wants to run in a mascot race.
陶彼德  您怎么说怎么是
For you, Torpedo, I'll make it happen.
我得空出一个角色服
I gotta free up one of these outfits.
不必了  我自己有
No, you don't! I got my own.
是个大汉堡
It's a burger.
-不错嘛  -非常感谢  陶彼德
- Easy enough. - Thanks a lot, Torpedo.
祝你好运  老兄
Good luck out there, Sport.
琳达  你  你听到了吗
Linda, did you-- did you hear that?
陶彼德・琼斯喊我"老兄"
Torpedo Jones called me "Sport".
他那不是喊你  他喊吉恩呢
He didn't call you "Sport", he called Gene "Sport".
不  他当时是看着我说的
No, he was looking right at me.
没错  他喊的是我  还抓了抓我的头发
Yeah, he called me "Sport" and he tussled my hair.
太棒了  吉恩  你真棒
It was great, Gene. You were great.
我就是招人抓的孩子
I'm a great tussle receiver.
在吉祥物赛跑上穿着汉堡服  吉恩
Wow, wearing the burger suit in the mascot race, Gene.
这是给老爸做广告啊
That's advertising, huh?
别碰我
Don't touch me!
陶彼德人真好  让我们坐在贵宾席
It was so nice of Torpedo to give us these seats
这样就能清楚观看吉恩的比赛了
so we can watch Gene's race.
在这里连球员的纹身都看得一清二楚
You can really make out the players' tattoos from here.
被遮住的纹身更让人浮想联翩
Makes you wonder about the tattoos we can't see.
纹在屁股上的
On their butts.
感觉怎么样  吉恩  心跳快吗
How you doing, Gene? You feeling fast?
不  我有点想吐
No, I feel queasy.
是不是很紧张呀  王牌
Got some butterflies, Ace?
-陶彼德  -想听听我的建议吗  孩子
- Torpedo! - Want my advice, kid?
这比赛要穿着角色服跑
It's a mascot race,
你需要做的就是稳住脚下
all you gotta do is stay on your feet.
让其他选手自乱阵脚
Let the other guys trip over themselves.
吉祥物赛跑的时间到了
It's time for the mascot race!
老天啊
Goodie.
记住  你是我们餐馆的形象大使
Remember, you're an ambassador for our restaurant,
跑两下意思意思就行了
so just trying and run well,
你本来跑得就不咋地
'cause you don't run well.
祝你好运  老兄
Good luck out there, Sport.
之前那句"老兄"  我还以为你在喊我呢
Oh. Yeah, I thought earlier you called me "Sport", so...
不  在那出现的孩子我都那么叫  闪兄
Nah, that was-- that was a nickname for the kid there, Flash.
那我就叫"闪兄"吧
I'll take "Flash".
孩子们  从现在起叫我"闪兄"
Kids, call me "Flash" from now on.
为了区分一下  还是叫你"臭兄"吧
Let's split the diff and call you "Stinky".
臭兄  我喜欢
Stinky! I like it!
陶彼德  为了感谢你让吉恩参赛
Oh, Torpedo, here's a little thank-you
这是一点小意思
for getting Gene in the race.
我是个卖汉堡的
I make burgers for a living,
所以给你这东西不算奇怪吧
so it's not weird for me to give you this.
我不觉得奇怪啊  鲍勃
I don't think it's weird at all, Bob.
装作好吃的样子吧
Like a good burger.
味道真的很好呢
Mmm. That's a good burger.
我去解决一下投球区的那个废柴
Finish this guy back on the mound.
陶彼德・琼斯刚刚夸我做的汉堡好吃哎
Ha! Torpedo Jones just said I make a good burger!
我想把那句话刻在我的墓碑上
I want that on my tombstone.
我没开玩笑  可以吗
Seriously, okay?
不行  你的墓志铭我已经替你选好了
No, I already got your tombstone picked out for ya.
什么  是什么
What, what is it?
"汉堡来喽"
It says, "Order up."
不错  就刻这个吧
That's good. Let's go with that one.
今天  加入出彩码头吉祥物赛跑的
Joining your Wonder Wharf mascots today
是一位特别的食物来宾
is a special guest food,
一个大汉堡
a burger!
操纵它的是一个男孩
A boy who is also a burger.
注意听令
And I have my gun.
预备  就位
Ready, set...
超过他们  吉恩
Go get 'em, Gene!
我强化了一下汉堡服的侧边
I reinforced the crotch
这样他就不会撕开它了
so he wouldn't tear it.
加油  吉恩  替亡父报仇
Win, Gene! Avenge dad's death!
海狮萨米倒下了
Down goes Sammy Sea Lion!
只剩下两个选手了
Ooh! It's a two-mascot race!
汉堡男孩和鹈鹕船长
Burger and Captain Pel-I-Can.
他们激烈地竞争着
There they go,
像两个踩着风火轮的...
like two, fast, fiery...
哪吒
bew!
汉堡男孩赢了
The burger is your winner!
祝贺你  汉堡小伙
Well, congratulations, young burger.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
您可以在公园内购买
you can purchase delicious burgers
差不多这个样子的
that look somewhat like him
超级美味汉堡
right here at the park.
还可以在我家餐馆购买
And at my family's restaurant.
你家餐馆叫什么
And, uh, what's the name of that restaurant?
是...  是...
Ah, it's-- it's--
-我每天都泡在那啊  -开心汉堡店
- God, I'm there every day. - Bob's Burgers!
-什么来的  神哪  -开心汉堡店
- It's-- Oh, God... - Bob's Burgers!
-吉恩  不  -算了算了  没关系
- Gene! No! - Never mind. Never mind. That's okay.
不管这家店叫什么
You can get everything you expect from a burger
你都可以点个汉堡  享受美味
at whatever the name of his restaurant is...
我想起来了  我想起来了
Oh, oh, I just remembered! I just remembered!
晚了
It's too late.
但你今天可以在公园买到
But you can get them here at the park, today.
不  说出来啊
No! Say it!
我赢了  赢了赢了  我赢了
I won something! I won! I won! I won something!
而且  你没有像其他人一样摔倒
Yeah, and you didn't fall down like everyone else.
-跟你的孙子们好好显摆显摆  -我会的
- Tell that to your grandkids. - I will.
吉恩  你真是坑爹呢啊
Gene, are you kidding me?!
我们家餐馆叫做  开心汉堡店
The name of the restaurant is Bob's Burgers!
可是  我喊你"老爸"的啊
Well, I call you "dad"!
我还以为叫"老爸汉堡店"呢
I think of it as Dad's Burgers!
你就睡在餐馆上面
You live above it!
你每天都在餐馆里干活啊
You work in it every day!
鲍勃  冷静  冷静
Bob, calm down, calm down.
我很抱歉  老爸
I'm sorry, dad.
我没事我没事  他很棒
I'm fine. I'm fine. He did great.
你很棒  吉恩
You did great, Gene.
金牌哎  我们应该给它镀层青铜
A gold medal! Oh, we should get that bronzed!
好球  三振出局
Strike three. You're out!
陶彼德的无影指叉球突然球风一转
Torpedo's split-finger skadootch has suddenly started clicking.
我好喜欢你做的汉堡  鲍勃
I love that burger of yours, Bob.
比赛结束后  我们去开心汉堡店闹一闹吧
Hey, after the game, let's all go to Bob's Burgers!
现在  有人给我宣传了
Now that's advertising, huh?
今日汉堡
我与汉堡有个约会
精制花生口味
上等汉堡  只要5.95
小天使
Ooh, Angel!
他们这么叫你  是因为你很乖吗
Do they call you that 'cause you're such a good boy?
为了逃出古巴  我做了很多坏事
I did many bad things to escape Cuba.
那些事总在无尽的暗夜中纠缠着我
Things that haunt me in the dark of the night.
再来杯啤酒吧
How about another beer?
兄弟  知道吗  你们的老爸非常赞
Man, you kids got a great dad, you know that?
一夫一妻一家庭  这样才对
One wife. One family. That's the way to do it.
知道么  职棒联盟的那些家伙
You know, in the majors, most guys got a whole bunch of families
一人娶遍50州
spread out over the 50 states.
春训时  佛罗里达的妻子相伴左右
When spring training starts, you get your Florida wife.
常规赛季  意味着"开放赛季"
When it's regular season, it's open season,
你们懂我在说什么吧
if you know what I'm talkin' about.
你吻别老家的农妇和孩子们
You kiss your home field wife and kids good-bye,
告诉他们你会想他们的  你也确实会
you tell 'em you'll miss 'em, and you do.
然后偷拿一些玩具  送给另一处的孩子
But you still take some of their toys and re-gift 'em for your away kids.
那你一定是个了不起的爸爸喽
I bet you're a great dad.
兼三个超级赞的丈夫
And three great husbands.
陶彼德先生  我无意中注意到
Mr. Torpedo, I couldn't help but notice
那个高个子男生有点无精打采的
that the tall boy was looking a little lethargic.
他生狼疮了  或是佝偻病犯了还是什么的
Yeah, he's got Lupus or rickets or somethin'.
我就纳闷为啥我们队总招这些病秧子
I don't know why we keep giving that job to these sick kids.
请问我能为您提供服务吗
I was wondering if I could offer my services.
我健康着呢
I'm very healthy.
行了行了行了  可以可以  别再拱了
Okay, okay, okay. Hey, you got the job. Just stop doing that.
你的第一个任务来了
Here's your first ball girl duty:
每场比赛前都给我带个汉堡
bringing me one of your dad's burgers before every game.
好的
Okay.
这是你想要的香烟
Here's the tabacco you wanted.
你想要的漫画
And your comic books.
答应你的事  我已搞定
那排失踪的玉米粒我换上新的了
费诺  同时爱上25个人  这有可能吗
Phe-Nom, is it possible to be in love with 25 people at once?
你是我的最爱
You're my favorite.
别告诉小天使  他火气大
Don't tell Angel. He's fiery.
三振出局
Strike three!
掌声雷动  因为陶彼德情绪高涨了起来
Sound the alarm because Torpedo is on fire!
狂热  狂热  狂热
Fire! Fire! Fire!
这样不好吧  伯特  体育场里人这么多
Not a good idea, Burt. It's a crowded stadium.
那个陶彼德真是超乎想象
That Torpedo is amazing!
他总是这么出色吗
Has he always been this good?
不  他低迷了很长一段时间
No, he hasn't been good in a long time.
他说我的汉堡帮他提高了投球技术呢
He says my burgers have helped him pitch better.
汉堡怎么会帮人提高投球技术呢
How does a burger help someone pitch better?
鲍勃  接着  小小纪念品
Here ya go, Bob, little souvenir.
多谢了  老兄
Thanks, buddy!
好滑啊
Whoa, slippery.
全都是油啊
It's greasy, huh?
一股什么味儿
What does this smell like?
别再闻陶彼德的蛋了
Hey, stop sniffing Torpedo's balls.
ball也有"睾丸"的意思
你明白吗
Get it?
你好像爱上了他
It's like you're in love with him.
等等  这是我们家汉堡味
Wait. That's our burger.
我擦  陶彼德往球上抹油了
Oh, crap. Torpedo's putting my grease on the ball.
怪不得他的"无影球"还好使呢
That's how his skadootch is skadootching so much.
你的英雄用你的汉堡油赢分  好棒
Your hero's using your burger grease to win. That's great!
不  琳  陶彼德在利用我的汉堡油作弊
No, Lin, Torpedo is using my burger grease to cheat.
这么说你无意中帮助陶彼德作弊了
So you helped Torpedo cheat.
如果奇葩狗还来餐馆吃饭
If that means the Wonderdogs keep coming to the restaurant
照顾我们家生意
bringing all sorts of business with them,
我就睁只眼闭只眼
I say big whoop,
让那个老男人投抹油的球吧
let the old man throw a greasy skadootch.
我都不知道该怎样看待这件事
I don't even know what to think about this.
我去尿泼尿
I gotta go take a leak.
给我带个小号冰淇淋回来
Oh, get me an ice cream in a mini helmet!
男厕
鲍勃  怎么闷闷不乐的啊
Bob. You look glum.
我...  那个...
Oh, I, uh...
你尿尿时  不扶着...  你的...
You... don't hold your... when you pee.
小鸡鸡吗
怎么  反正它又不会乱跑
Why? It's not going anywhere.
好吧
Okay.
如果你发现  某个你认识的人
Um, well, what if you found out that someone you knew
正在做一些不太光明的事
was doing something sort of bad,
而你无意中成了帮凶...
and you were helping them do that sort of bad thing...
说我呢吗  你指堕胎吗
Is it me? Is it abortions?
-等等  什么  -你刚才说什么了
- Wait. What? - Uh, what were you saying?
陶彼德・琼斯往球上抹油
Torpedo Jones is greasing the ball,
那是我家汉堡上的油
and he's using my grease to do it.
跟我来
Oh. Come walk with me.
来看看幕后吧
Come behind the scenes!
陶彼德那眩目的球技
Torpedo's dazzling pitching
吸引越来越多的人前来观看比赛
is putting more butts in seats
多到体育场都快装不下了
than this stadium can handle.
没有那些高厚木板支撑
Is the roller coaster going to be okay
这辆过山车不会出问题吗
without those huge planks of wood?
没问题  没问题
Sure, sure!
这些人不会为多余的木头付钱  鲍勃
These people aren't paying for extra wood, Bob.
没人想乘坐"多余木山车"
No one wants to ride Extra Wood Mountain.
小心这些多余的螺帽和螺栓
Whoa! Watch out! Extra nuts and bolts.
人们来看棒球比赛
People come to baseball games
和去游乐场是出于同一种原因
for the same reason they come to the amusement park:
都是为了找乐子
to be entertained!
有没有暗箱操作关系大吗  不大
Does it really matter if the games are rigged? No!
-比赛有暗箱  -是的
- The games are rigged? - Yes!
哎哟  我的小鸡鸡怎么还在外面
Oh, my wonderdog is hanging out.
是啊  是啊
Yes. Yes, it is.
我聊得太投入了
I got so caught up in our conversation,
拉链都忘了拉
I forgot to zip.
我不想发表意见
Yeah, I didn't want to say anything.
-为什么  -我...
- Why not? - I, uh...
好听的话不嫌多  我刚才说到哪了
Compliments are welcome. Where was I?
你刚才说  比赛有暗箱
You were saying the games are rigged.
没错  所有比赛  游戏  都被暗箱了
Yes. The games are all rigged.
这些游戏我不会再让孩子们玩了
I'm not letting my kids play these games anymore.
你看这些开心的脸
But look at these smiling faces,
就和那些开心的脸一样
just like those smiling faces.
陶彼德的每个无影球都给大家带来了无尽的欢乐
Smiling at every skadootch the Torpedo throws.
他们不想知道真相  鲍勃
They don't want to know, Bob.
他们不想看到"帷幕后的景象"
They don't want to "look behind the curtain".
我不知道
I don't know.
也许  善恶各有报应
It just seems like bad karma or something.
报应  这世上哪有"报应"一说啊
Karma? There's no such thing as "karma".
至少不会在本市出现
Not in this town.
快踢掉  快把它们踢到海里去
Oh, just kick 'em. Kick 'em right into the ocean!
-好  -好了
- Okay. - That's it.
等等  为什么陶纳德想要一罐用过的油
Wait, why does Tornado want our old grease in a jar?
Tornado:  龙卷风
是陶彼德  吉恩
It's Torpedo, Gene.
陶彼德:  鱼雷
这会帮他投出好球
Uh, it helps him pitch better.
还有  记住  这是秘密
And-- and don't forget, it's a secret.
怎么  这样做是违规的么
Why? Is it against the rules?
严格说来  是的
Technically, yes.
那这是作弊喽
So then it's cheating.
不  这样做
No. What it is,
是帮助大家享受更多看球的乐趣
is helping people enjoy baseball more.
这是在  取悦大家
It's entertainment.
我不明白
I'm confused.
你和妈妈要离婚了吗
Are you and mom getting divorced?
-什么  -天哪  还真是
- What? - Oh, my God, you are.
-我跟老妈  -我跟老爸
- I call mom! - I call dad!
你俩把爸妈都给占了
You guys took both of them.
够了  给我装调料去
Enough. Go fill the condiments.
-我装番茄酱  -我装芥末酱
- I call ketchup! - I call mustard!
你可以装辣根酱
You can do horseradish.
又没有...  好的
There's not... Okay.
谢谢  老鲍
Thanks, Bobby.
谁想吃汉堡  我请客
Hey, who wants a burger on the Torpedo!
万岁
Hooray!
吉恩  你要卫冕哦  紧张吗
Gene, you're defending your title. Are you nervous?
你怎么不问问我拉肚子好没好
Why don't you ask my diarrhea.
你应该感到紧张
You should be nervous.
你这个穿着汉堡服的胖小子
You're a chubby kid in a mascot suit.
这正是我想说的  我应该作作弊
That's what I'm saying. I should cheat.
老爸也说过  如果是为了取乐就可以作弊
Dad says it's okay when it's for entertainment.
没错  我们作弊吧
That's right! Let's cheat!
-看到那只鹈鹕了吗  -看到了
- You see that pelican? - Yeah.
你用跑的  对吧
You're running, right?
你往鞋上绑把弹簧刀
You have a switchblade taped to your shoe.
-他有装吗  -他会装的
- He does? - He will.
在另外一只鞋上绑个柠檬
And on your other shoe, you'll have a lemon.
捅死你  捅死你  捅死你
Stab! Stab! Stab!
蜇死你  蜇死你  蜇死你
Sting, sting, sting!
"你在干什么"
"What are you doing?"
"我在往你的伤口里挤柠檬汁"
"I'm squeezing lemon into your wound!"
甜心宝贝刀锋脚
Sweet baby, blade foot.
我也可以用手肘撞他  然后使绊子
Or... I can give him a nudge and tip him over.
这样行么
Ugh, really?
行  他头重脚轻
Yeah. He's top-heavy.
我只要轻轻拍一下就行了
I'll just give him a little tippity-tap.
我还是坚持在脚底绑刀
Well, I'm still gluing a knife to my foot.
吉恩加油  吉恩快跑
Yay, Gene! Go, Gene!
就是这样  儿子
That-a-way, son!
轻轻拍一下
Tippity-tap.
三个吉祥物连环相撞
It's a three-mascot-pileup!
吉恩快跑  吉恩好样的
Go, Gene! All right! Go!
汉堡男孩又赢了
The Boy Burger wins again!
你认为怎么样
How about that?
你认为怎么样  菲尔
Hey, how about this, Phil?
我不知道  伯特  我不是很确定
I don't know, Burt. I'm not so sure about that.
我赢了  我又赢了
I won! I won again!
我弟弟赢了
My brother won!
伙计们  快脱掉球衫
Guys, take off your shirts.
手臂甩得很起劲嘛  宝贝
Good arm pumping, baby!
很好地掩饰了我推人这招
That's how I disguised the push.
你推人了
What push?
他把棉花糖推倒了
He pushed the Cotton Candy mascot so he'd fall over.
作弊万岁
Hooray for cheating!
吉恩  你怎么能这样  这样做是错的
Gene, how could you? You know that's wrong.
不不不  如果是为了取乐  就不是错的
Uh-uh-uh. Not when it's entertainment.
你自己说的
You said it yourself.
这是你教的么
You told them cheating is okay?
不  我没有  琳达
No, I didn't, Linda.
就是他教的
Yes, he did.
-鲍鲍  -糟糕
-Oh, Bobby. -Oh, crap.
去给我买个蛋卷冰淇淋  要经典造型的
Go get me a soft serve. And make it a swirl!
吉恩  我那句"作弊没关系"
Look, Gene, when I said it's okay to cheat,
是说陶彼德作弊没关系
I meant for Torpedo,
不是说你作弊没关系
not for you to cheat in your mascot race.
你应该还回去一块金牌
You should really give back one of those medals.
但在还之前  我想给你照张相
Ooh, but I want to get a picture of you wearing them before you do.
我才不要还
I'm not giving back my medals!
那些混蛋花钱花得值啊  老爸
Those suckers got their money's worth, pops.
你看我很有商业头脑吧  老爸
I'm good for business, dad.
从现在开始  不许再作弊
You know what? From now on, there'll be no more cheating.
也就是说我不应该再给陶彼德送油了是吧
Does that mean I shouldn't give Torpedo this grease?
没错  蒂娜
That's right, Tina.
是的  这个家不许再有人作弊
Yes. No more cheating for anyone in this house.
从今往后  我再也不穿收腹牛仔裤了
From now on, I won't wear my tummy tuck jeans.
再见  巴西佬  你好  热带雨林
And goodbye, Brazilian. Hello, rainforest.
抱歉  老爸
Sorry, Dad.
但如果明天我赢了  我将是有史以来
But if I win tomorrow, I'll be the first mascot
第一个三连胜的吉祥物
ever to win three races in a row.
多V5啊
I'm a top!
你的意思是  "威武"么
You mean you're on top.
不  是"V5"
No. I'm a top!
我还以为
Shew. I was starting to think
你会放我鸽子呢
maybe you were going to leave me high and dry here.
这只罐里的东西  值得你等待
Well, what's in this jar is worth the wait.
搞什么...
What the...?
无需作弊
"You don't need to cheat.
没有我  你也能赢
"You can win without me.
全力以赴  就是冠军
"If you try your hardest, you've already won.
爱你  鲍家汉堡油
"Love, Bob's grease."
没错  陶彼德
That's right, Torpedo.
没有油你也能赢
You can win without my grease.
我对你有信心
It just took me believing in you.
听着  吉恩等会就要开跑了
Now, listen. Gene's about to race,
你是他的偶像
and since you're his role model,
所以我希望你能告诉他
I'm hoping you'll tell Gene
不作弊也能赢  就像你一样
he can win without cheating, just like you.
吉恩是哪只鸟
Who the hell's Gene?
他是...  我儿子
That's... my son.
你是他的偶像  也是我的偶像
You're his role model, and you're my role model, too.
擦  我怎么能是你的偶像  我们同龄啊
Wha...? I can't be your role model, we're the same age.
这是什么意思  你不再给我送油了吗  爆勃
What's this mean? You cutting me off, Bobo?
陶彼德  我在帮你释放自己
Torpedo, I'm cutting you free.
-过来  -等等  你想干什么
- Come here. - Wait, what are you going to do?
-我想抱抱你  -慢着  大老虎
- I'm going to hug you. - Slow down there, tiger.
看来我得用这瓶油撑过这一季了
Guess I'll have to make this grease last the whole season.
我就不应该给你提供油
I should have never given you my grease.
我亲手造就了一个怪物
I created a monster.
你以为遇见你之后我才开始用油作弊吗
You think you started my greasing?
我的职业生涯一直都在作弊  老鲍
I've always cheated, Bobby.
至少凌波微球没有作弊啊
Not the... "the pitch".
凌波微球当然作弊了
Oh, definitely "the pitch".
那场比赛  我在鼻孔里藏了块黄油
That game, I had a pat of butter in my nostril,
在腋下抹了点润滑剂
sex jelly in my armpit...
我还吃了几片处方药
Hell, I was on prescription drugs
以刺激耳屎生长
to stimulate production of earwax.
什么"凌波微球"
And "the pitch"?
全靠从黑市的爱斯基摩人手里
That was courtesy of some black market whale blubber
买到的鲸脂
I bought off some Eskimos.
这个纸条还是很有爱的  鲍勃
Cute note, though, Bob.
我建议你  下次找偶像找个老一点的
Bit of advice: if you want a role model, pick an old guy.
等你长大了  他们也死翘翘了
By the time you grow up, they're dead.
不太顺利啊
Didn't go great.
-吉恩  -我看肯定行
- Gene! - I'm sure it was fine.
陶彼德看上去是个讲理的人
Torpedo seems like a reasonable guy.
陶彼德・琼斯要你们即刻离席
Torpedo Jones wants you out of his seats this second.
-混蛋一个  -吉恩
- What a schmuck. - Gene!
第七局中场休息
It's the seventh-inning stretch.
吉祥物们已经站好队了
Mascots are lining up.
我想我有主意了
All right, maybe I have an idea.
兄弟
Hi, fellas,
我想跟我儿子说几句话
I'd love to say a few words to my son,
穿汉堡服那个  不好意思
the burger, over the PA. Excuse me.
好吧  突发状况哟
Uh... okay. Highly unusual.
不重要  这一切都不重要
Doesn't matter. None of this matters.
吉恩
Gene.
往上瞅
Up here.
上帝吗
Jesus?
不  吉恩  是你老爸啦  我在上面
No, Gene, it's your father. I'm up here.
你死了吗
You're dead?!
没错
Yes.
好啦  我开玩笑的
No, I'm kidding.
我在解说台里  这边  看到了吗
I'm up here in the booth. Right here. See me?
我去  这麦怎么有股啤酒味
Boy, this microphone smells like beer.
戒酒互助会都纯"扯蛋"
Well, let's just say AA was "A" waste of time.
夺冠不是最重要的  吉恩
Winning isn't everything, Gene.
没错  我们来这儿是为了开心
Yes, we're all here to be entertained,
但如果你投机取巧
but if you, um, cut corners now,
也许你今后就会
the next thing you know, you'll be
往鼻孔里藏猪油
hiding lard in your nose
或者搭建过山车时偷工减料
or taking wood out of roller coasters.
我说你说够了没有
Hey, all right, that's enough of that.
开始比赛吧
Let's start the race!
我正跟我儿子说话呢
I'm trying to talk to my son.
吉恩  不要作弊
Gene, run clean.
各就各位
On your mark!
吉恩  你打算怎么做
Gene, what are you going to do?
我不知道
I don't know.
你要作弊
You're going to cheat!
你要这样做
That's what you're going to do!
你要靠作弊夺冠
You're going to win by cheating!
有没有人想看汉堡男孩三连冠啊
Who wants to see the Burger win three in a row?
吉恩  听我说  你知道该怎么做
Gene, listen to me. You know what to do.
鲍勃  小汉堡要三连冠哦
Bob... triple crown for Burger.
对你的生意也有好处哦
Good for your business.
听到没
See?!
不  吉恩  别想着打广告了
No, Gene! Don't worry about the advertising.
你们这是干嘛  那只是发令枪罢了
What are you doing? It's a starter's pistol.
那是真枪  我劝你也躲起来
It's a real gun. You should get down.
什么  别打了  真荒唐
What?! Stop shooting! This is crazy.
好  他不打了
Oh, good. He stopped.
他只是子弹用完了
He's just out of bullets.
棉花糖倒下了
And down goes Cotton Candy!
现在是两人争夺赛
It's a two-mascot race.
吉恩  别做傻事
Gene. Do the right thing.
没错  吉恩  你可以的
Yeah. You can win on your own, Gene!
大概吧
Probably.
好吧  好吧
All right. Fine.
怎么是你推他  应该是他推你啊
Don't push him! He was going to push you!
祝贺鹈鹕船长
Congratulations to Captain Pel-I-Can!
吉恩  我很抱歉  孩子
Oh, Gene. Sorry, buddy.
看来报应在你身上灵验了
I mean, looks like karma caught up to you.
鲍勃  跟你说过  世上没有报应这回事
Bob, I told you there's no such thing as karma.
我看有
Uh, yes, there is.
我看没有
No, I'm afraid there isn't!
-有  -没有
- I'm afraid there is. - Is not.
我勒个去
Oh, crap.
看到没  吉恩  这就是作弊的后果
See, Gene. This is what happens when you cheat.
太不可思议了
That was incredible!
作弊好酷哦
Cheating is amazing!
鲍勃
Bob?
你好
Oh. Uh, hi.
你的过山车变成这样  我很难过
Sorry about your roller coaster.
哎  建了塌  塌了修嘛
Ah, roller coasters come and go.
而你鲍勃  一生难求
But Bobs are once in a lifetime.
我很敬佩你
I admire you.
-是吗  -你让我想起了我的父亲
- You do? - You remind me of my father.
他很正直  勤勤恳恳
He was honest, and he worked hard.
你是移民吗  鲍勃
You an immigrant, Bob?
不是
Um... no.
-天生的猩猩体质吗  -大概吧
- Just swarthy? - I guess.
-"猩猩体质"是啥意思  -又黑又多毛
- What's "swarthy"? - Um, dark and hairy.
就是你啦  也是未来的我
That's you! And me in the future.
跟你不同  我父亲赚了很多钱
Well, unlike you, my father made a fortune.
但在其它方面  你们有很多相同之处
But in many other ways, you guys are the same.
比如  你们都很正直  也都很像猩猩
Two decent, swarthy peas in a pod.
然而一个富有  而另一个...
One rich, one...
-勉强维持生计  -谢谢
- just scraping by. - Thanks.
好了  我要去做按摩了
Well, we're off to get a massage.
走吧  小鸡鸡  安分点儿
Come on, Wonderdog. Down, boy.
他走了  老爸  我未来的老公走了
He's gone, dad. My future husband's gone.
是你把他赶走的
You drove him away!
蒂娜  你手上拿的什么
Tina, what you got there?
队员们签过名的棒球
The team signed a ball,
给我留作纪念的
so I'd have something to remember them by.
我还拿了个下体保护带
And I took this jockstrap.
好了  宝贝
Okay, sweetie.
-我们把它扔了吧  -不要
- Let's throw that in the wash. - No.
快点  给我
Come on, give it to me.
你知道那些球员身上染过多少性病吗
Do you know how many venereal diseases those baseball players have?
我不在乎
I don't care.
这是谁的
Whose was it?
-闻着像是小天使的  -小天使的
- Smells like Angel. - Angel.
别告诉费诺哦
But don't tell Phe-Nom.